Guide to the Charles J. Sullivan Letters SC0962
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles J. Sullivan letters
1918-1921
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sullivan, Charles J.
SC0962
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
These letters were written to his fiancée Rowena Gray, in Chowchilla, CA, while Sullivan was at Stanford and training for the military, 1918, and then working in Los Angeles, June-August 1919, and Salinas, 1919-21. His 1918 letters discuss life at Stanford, his military training in the Students Army Training Corps, his bout of influenza and time at the Camp Fremont hospital, the death of “Swede” (a member of his fraternity Delta Tau Delta), and his relationship with Rowena. When he was working and separated from Rowena he wrote to her almost every day, and sometimes twice a day. His letters generally talked about his work, his social activities, family affairs, and their relationship. His letters from Los Angeles include watching the arrival of the Pacific Fleet in Long Beach, August 1919; a visit to a San Pedro shipyard and his attempt to get a tour of the Mississippi, August 1919; and the adverse affect of the labor strike in LA on transportation and other aspects of daily life.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Charles J. Sullivan attended Stanford University 1916-18; he married Rowena Gray on Feb. 12, 1920.
Description of the Collection
These letters were written to his fiancée Rowena Gray, in Chowchilla, CA, while Sullivan was at Stanford and training for the military, 1918, and then working in Los Angeles, June-August 1919, and Salinas, 1919-21. His 1918 letters discuss life at Stanford, his military training in the Students Army Training Corps, his bout of influenza and time at the Camp Fremont hospital, the death of “Swede” (a member of his fraternity Delta Tau Delta), and his relationship with Rowena. When he was working and separated from Rowena he wrote to her almost every day, and sometimes twice a day. His letters generally talked about his work, his social activities, family affairs, and their relationship. His letters from Los Angeles include watching the arrival of the Pacific Fleet in Long Beach, August 1919; a visit to a San Pedro shipyard and his attempt to get a tour of the Mississippi, August 1919; and the adverse affect of the labor strike in LA on transportation and other aspects of daily life.
Los Angeles (Calif.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century.; Sullivan, Charles J.; Sullivan, Charles J.
- Correspondence, 1918-1921
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 Feb-July (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 August-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 October 8-12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 October 13-17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 October 18-20 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 October 21-124 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 October 26-30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 Nov. 1-5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1918 Nov. 6-18 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 May 3-22 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 May 24-31 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 June 1-5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 June 6-9 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 June 10-15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 June 16-24 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 June 25-30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 July 11-18 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 July 19-22 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 July 23-31 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 August 1-12 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 August 14-19 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 August 20-25 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 October 10-15 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 October 16-20 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 October 21-19 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 November 1-9 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 November 10-16 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 November 17-30 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 December 2-8 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 December 9-16 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 December 17-25 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1919 December 27-31 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, 1920 January-May (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray Sullivan, 1921 February 9-15 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray Sullivan, 1921 February 16-22 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray Sullivan, 1921 February 23-28 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray Sullivan, 1921 March (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Charles to Rowena Gray, undated (one written from Los Angeles, one from Salinas) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Rowena Gray from Grace Pattersonand her mother, 1919, 1920-21 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Charles to his son Charles Jr., 1921 Feb 19 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 3, Folder 14)